Finding aid for the Barbara Aziz broadcasts collection
Bentley Historical Library
- Radio Tahrir and related material, 1989-2014
  - February 11, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:35:52); (Aziz reflections on Muslim holiday and anticipating US attack on Iraq, listener. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Muslim Eid Special, NJ-local community leader Mohammed Kairallah. Topics: Muslim festival, Eid, anti-war actions, world music.)
  - April 1, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:26); (Rachida Mohammedi, interviewed in Iraq, speaks about Iraqi intellectuals, and the meaning of \'stone" in art and ongoing Palestinian resistance to occupation, relation between Iraq and Palestinian struggle. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet and editor/translator Rachida Mohammedi. Topics: Iraq, Iraqi writers, Palestine, world music.)
  - April 8, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:06); (Hagopian reports arrest of Ashraf Al-Bayoumi and other protesters against Iraq war, siege on Palestinian camps, Dr Nafii reports on restoration of health and hospital services, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Boston-based professor of sociology Elaine Hagopian, Iraq Kerbala hospital Dr. Karim Nafii. Topics: Egypt, US policy, war in Iraq, Iraq anti-war movement, Palestine-Israel "Road Map", Iraq health conditions.)
  - April 28, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:00:30); (Ajami on her film "Queen of the Gypsies" about revolutionary Spanish dancer Carmen Amaya and Islamic influence, callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Boston-based filmmaker Joyce Ajami, Aziz commentary on Iraq and war. Topics: Spanish Gypsy dance history, US policy on Iraq, world music, listener callins.)
  - May 6, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:57); (RankaManis announces NY-theater performance on Mindanao-Philippines Muslim political struggle, and political developments in Mindanao, with studio performance, comedian Malik tells jokes. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Potri RankaManis, NY-based Philippine activist/performer, Fawzia A Khan poem, comedian Nasri Malik. Topics: Mindanao Philippines political theater, Arab American Comedy, world music.)
  - June 10, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:58); (Rizgar Koshnow, author of "Nothing Left but Their Voices," describes conditions in Iraq Kurdistan and comments on war, Maysoon Zayid talks about her work as comedian. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: US Iraqi Kurd Rizgar Koshnow, US Arab American comedian Maysoon Zayid. Topics: Iraq, Iraqi Kurd, world music, Arab American comedy.)
  - June 17, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:29); (Aziz reports from DC conference of Arab Americans and its prospects as a nationwide organization, Chehade discusses her book and criticism of racial identities, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Aziz report from DC, NJ based author Carol Chehade of "Big Little White Lies". Topics: Arab Americans, African American and white identities.)
  - July 1, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:39:37); (Aziz speaks with Iraqi orchestral leader in Baghdad pre-invasion Dec 2002, Patricia Ward talks about her new novel, "The Bullet Collection," set in Lebanon. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Iraqi orchestral leader, NY-author novelist Arab Patricia Ward. Topics: Iraq, Iraqi musicians, UN sanctions, world music, Arab American literature, Lebanon.)
  - July 8, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:31:34); (Souad Al-Radi speaks about her life as a multi-cultural Iraqi, reviewing her life throughout the 20th C, a rare portrait of an Iraqi woman. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Baghdad resident Souad Al-Radi. Topics: Iraq, women, Middle East, history, world music.)
  - July 15, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:23); (Imam Jaber reports on accident at NJ mosque, poet Brookings talks about his "Islamic" poems and work as a spoken word poet, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NJ-based Imam Ali Jaber, NJ-based poet Dasham Brookings. Topics: Muslim American, Mosque fire, poetry, world music.)
  - July 22, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:01); (Poem "13&" by intern Amal Bishara, Rashida A Hakim and Mariam Bimji report relief work with ICNA in NY area and 911 Relief Project, program, Pourzal talks about benefits and limits of post Islamic revolution in Iran, world music. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Islamic Circle of North America health advisors Rachida Abdul Hakim and Mariam Bimji, US Iranian observer Ros Pourzal, poet Amal Bishara. Topics: Muslim Americans, NY area relief, Iran, world music.)
  - July 29, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:10); (Salim Rizvi and others announce national immigrant rally and meeting to highlight issues confronting Muslim immigrants and strategies, Bina Sharif reads her satirical play and talks about theatrical arts, Islamic principles. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Pakistani performer writer Bina Sharif, Immigrant workers freedom ride members Salim Rizvi and Zaheed Ali. Topics: Muslim American theater, immigrant civil rights, US immigration policy, satire and politics, world music.)
  - August 5, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:17); (Aziz talks about her professional relation with Huda Ammash, US accusations against Ammash, interview with Ammash in Baghdad on her research on chemical contamination and health issues in Iraq, listener callins Interviewees/Guests: Iraqi professor and scientist Dr. Huda Ammash. Topics: Iraq, UN sanctions, health conditions, contamination of Iraqi environment.)
  - August 12, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:51); (Episode on Iraqi and Palestinian prisoners)
  - August 26, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:01); (Aliya Sousa (who recently died in Iraq) speaking about her illustrious father scientist Ahmed Sousa (from earlier interview in Baghdad), Aziz commentary on Aliya Sousa, Rachida Mohammedi comments on colonialism and biased media, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah, Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian author poet Rachida Mohammedi, Iraqi economist Aliya Sousa. Topics: Iraq, history of Iraqi Ahmed Sousa, Algeria, media criticism.)
  - September 2, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:18); (Memorial to producer Safia Bhukari by NY area Muslims and women in leadership, Al-Azawi interviewed in Jordan by Aziz introduces us to new community art center, civil rights and literature talk by Suheir Hammad. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Director Women in Islam Aisha Adawiya, poet Suheir Hammad lecture at NJ-literary conference, Magdeline Al-Azawi, head of new Jordan Art Center (Dara al-Anda). Topics: Muslim Americans, women, civil rights, censorship, Arab Art Center, Jordan, world music.)
  - September 9, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:19); (Replay of Iraq interviews productions by Aziz; documentary "Iraq: How Can I Forget?"; Aliya Sousa, poem by Bushra Bustani. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Iraq special-- "Iraq How Can I Forget?"; biographer Aliya Sousa, Iraqi musicians, poet Bushra Bustani, doctors. Topics: Iraq, sanctions, history of Iraq, health.)
  - September 16, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:11); (Guests announce action in solidarity with Palestine, to advance economic divestment in Israel, Chahade discusses race issues in politics and economics, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NJ Author Carol Chehade, members of Palestinian Al-Awda, Rahma and Kamal of Malcolm X org, Lamis of Palestine Divestment conference. Topics: Palestine, civil rights, anti-occupation rally.)
  - September 23, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:58); (Reports on BDS Palestine US Divestment conference, guest talks about Bloods, Cripps and Lings gangs' Muslim roots in Italy and Spain, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Palestine solidarity student leader, Dr Mohammed and Gregory. Topics: reports on BDS Palestine US Divestment conference, guest talks about Bloods, Cripps and Lings gangs' Muslim roots in Italy and Spain, listener calls.)
  - September 30, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:26); (Aziz comments on Andalusian music tradition from Algeria, and reviews Said's work and life and struggle, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Aziz commentary. Topics: Aziz comments on Andalusian music tradition from Algeria, US intellectual Columbia U. professor Edward Said, Andalusian music, world music.)
  - October 7, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:53:38); (Nassef introduces us to the relation of Sunni and Shiia schools of Islam and describes their history and evolution. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based historian Ahmed Nassef, editor of MuslimWakeUp.com. Topics: Islam, Sunni/Shia, World music.)
  - October 14, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:55); (Nahla Saleh announces 3rd Palestine solidarity conference on US campuses, Safi and Haeri analyze positive Iranian response to Ebeidi's Nobel Prize award, and review US-Iran relations and conditions in Iran and offer background to Ebeidi. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Colgate U Professors Omid Safi and Boston U. Shahla Haeri, Palestine Solidarity movement Nahla Saleh. Topics: Palestine solidarity DBS divestment, Iran, Nobel Peace Laureate Shereen Obeidi, civil rights, world music.)
  - November 4, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:51:34); (Aziz comments on Ramadan gatherings, Al-Arian updates us on discrimination against persecution of Muslim Americans around the case of Sami Al-Arian. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Laila Al-Arian daughter of US Muslim political prisoner Sami Al-Arian. Topics: Ramadan, Islam, Civil Rights, Sami Al-Arian, World music, children.)
  - November 11, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:56); (To celebrate Ramadan, PA-based Muslim poet Abdu Hayy Moore reads Ramadan poetry and we play Lebanon children's songs, Dean Obeidallah reviews coming NYC Arab American Comedy Festival, comedy talent, Qumseiya describes Israeli apartheid wall. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: PA-based poet Abdu Hayy Moore, comedian Dean Obeidallah, CT-based Palestinian activist Mazen Qumseiya. Topics: Palestine, Israeli separation wall, Arab American comedy, world music.)
  - November 18, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:38); (Ramadan recitation by schoolgirl Abdul Majid, Aisha Adawiya announces Ramadan food drive, Maurii Saalakhan arrest and detention of Muslim American leader Abdul Rahman Al-Amoudi of American Muslim Foundation. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: DC-based Peace and Justice Foundation Muslim civil rights worker Maurii Saalakhan, Women in Islam leader Aisha Adawiya. Topics: Ramadan, Islam, Civil Rights, Qur'an, children, world music, religious music.)
  - December 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:46); (Abu Jaber speaks to Aziz about latest novel "Crescent", Aziz comments on socio-economic issues in Algeria, global influences, compositions by Algerian composer musician Farid Makhloufi recorded live in South Algeria. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: US Arab novelist Diana Abu Jaber, Algerian musician Farid Makhloufi. Topics: Arab American Literature, Algeria, world music.)
  - December 16, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:41); (Abdul Gafour describes women\'s magazine "Azizah" and its goals, Lynne Stewart reviews government indictment and case against her, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: US magazine editor Salimah Abdul Gafour, NJ civil rights worker Magdy Mahmoud, NY civil rights attorney. Topics: Muslim Americans, Muslim media, civil rights, secret evidence, world music.)
  - December 23, 2003, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:08); (Aziz commentary, reading of children\'s poems, reading of "Sura of Miriam" on birth of Jesus (with translation). Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Christmas special. Topics: Christmas Special, Quran, world music.)
  - January 6, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:42); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring John Cowie; Tony Shalhoub; and Najla Said and Maha Shahlawi, co-founders of Nibras, Arab American Theater Collective. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American Arts and Comedy.)
  - January 20, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 1:10:15); (Zayid comments on Fen Mejnoon show on Tahrir, commentary in Arabic on MLK by Mohammedi, interview with Algerian resistance fighter Saadi Yusuf (Arabic and English), comparison of occupation of Iraq today and Algeria in 20th Century. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based comedians Maysoon Zayid and Dean Obeidallah, Algerian poet Rachida Mohammedi, Algerian resistance film actor Saadi Yusuf. Topics: world music, commentary in Arabic on Martin Luther King, fundraising, Algeria.)
  - February 17, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:03); (Rachida Mohammedi offers Arabic audio commentary on art and politics, Dr. F. Khan counters criticism of lslam and Muslims by US Rep Peter King; Abla Khoury talks about her performance and directing at New York's LaMama theater, film review. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet Rachida Mohammedi, Dr Faroque Khan president of NY Islamic Center, theater director Abla Khoury. Topics: commentary in Arabic on art and politics, Muslim Americans, anti-Islam, Africa Arab world, world music, Lebanon theater.)
  - February 24, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:38); (Mohammedi comments on economic exploitation of African in her "Legacy of Gold Mines", Zogby comments on Ralph Nader in politics, al-Mufti and Khederi criticize US humanitarian work in Iraq during embargo and occupation. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet Rachida Mohammedi; Jim Zogby of Arab American Institute; Iraqi journalist Nermin Al-Mufti. Topics: commentary in Arabic, world music, Arabs in US politics, Iraq.)
  - March 2, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:20); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring Tarek Aboushi, Peter Fetoush, and Kathy Najimy. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy.)
  - March 9, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:39); (Mohammedi's Arabic commentary on women's lives, Iraq, anti-war poem by Fawzia Afzal Khan, US Muslim leader Gazi Khankan comments on anti-Muslim remarks by congressman Peter King, Aziz reads essay on Iraq and women. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet Rachida Mohammadi, NY community leader Gazi Khankan, assistant producer Saadia Aslam. Topics: Arabic commentary, women, world music, Muslim Americans, civil rights.)
  - March 16, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:44); (Mohammedi\'s Arabic commentary "Woman to Woman", El-Montasar talks about working with schools and education about local Muslims, listener callins. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet Rachida Mohammedi, cultural diversity consultant Debbie Al-Montasar. Topics: Arabic commentary, women, world music, Muslim Americans, .)
  - March 30, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:27); (Mohammedi\'s Arabic commentary "Land Day", Ahmed talks about Brooklyn Jazz Festival, discussion of taking the land with Native American Tiokasan and US-Palestinian professor Nasser Aruri, world music. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet Rachida Mohammedi, Native American producer Tiokasin Ghosthorse, US Prof. Dartmouth U. Nasir Aruri, NY-Jazz performer musician Ahmed Abdallah. Topics: Palestine, Israeli occupation, US Native American history, world music.)
  - April 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:44); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring Betty Shamieh, Ann-Marie Jacir, and Helen Malik. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy.)
  - April 13, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:58:32); (Mohammedi presents commentary in Arabic on US United Nations Rep. Condoleezza Rice, guests help define progressive Muslim movement, and diversity of Muslim Americans, and question their leadership, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet and translator Rachida Mohammedi, Sarah Al-Tanatawi IMPAC, editor Ahmed Nassef (MuslimWakeup.com) with interns Saadia Aslam, Imran Ahmed and Kareem Freeman. Topics: progressive Islam, Muslim Americans.)
  - circa April 20, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:41:13); (Mohammedi's Arabic language commentary on new world terrorism, Shahram Shiva describes history and meaning of Rumi's work with recitations from his new CD, Algeria ambassador Jazzeri reviews history of Algeria and US. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet and translator Rachida Mohammedi, Sufi interpreter Shahram Shiva, Algerian Ambassador Idris Jazzeri to US. Topics: Sufi poet Rumi, Algeria, US-Algeria relations, world music.)
  - April 20, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:21); (Ambassador Jazzeri talks about 2003 earthquake, editor Laila Amatalaverain talks with Kareem Freeman about her writing, Shahram Shiva speaks about poetry and Rumi. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algeria Ambassador Idris Jazzeri, NY-Muslim African American writer Laila Amatalaverain, Rumi translator Shahram Shiva. Topics: Algeria, US-Algeria relations, world music, Muslim Americans, Sufi poet Rumi.)
  - April 27, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:20); (Rachida Mohammedi reads commentary in Arabic "From Humus to Edward Said"; world music, Prof Omid Safi defines range of Islam and progressive Islam movement, Zaima Motakabir speaks with Saadia Aslam about Sadila House, NJ shelter for Women. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: Algerian poet Rachida Mohammedi, and interns, Saadia Aslam speaks with Zaima Motakabir Director of Sadika House; Colgate University Professor Omid Safi; NY based poet Ngoma. Topics: Muslim Americans, poetry, commentary in Arabic, progressive Islam, women\'s services.)
  - May 4, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:50); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring Rania Khalil, Omar Matwally, and Adam Matta. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy-- in several tracks.)
  - June 15, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:43); (Members of Tahrir\'s production team discuss journalist Manji\'s controversial book "The Trouble With Islam". Hosts/Producer: Imran Ahmed. Interviewees/Guests: production assistants Imran Ahmed, Saadia Aslam, poet Rachida Mohammedi and Kareem Freeman. Topics: Muslim Americans, progressive Isalm, author/journalist Irshad Manji, world music.)
  - June 20, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:43); (Casanova talks about his family history and ambitions and work as a tenor, with clips form his operas; Nihad Dukhan discusses his training as a calligrapher and his innovations. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Dominican-US tenor Francisco Shaheen Casanova, Michigan calligrapher Nihad Dukhan. Topics: Palestine, Arab American artists, calligraphy.)
  - June 22, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:51:25); (Feisel Raouf talks about his book "What\'s Right With Islam" and interpretations about Islam and Muslim countries, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NY Imam Feisel Raouf author of "What\'s Right with Islam". Topics: Islam, Muslim Americans, the Qur\'an, Muslim history.)
  - July 6, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:54:54); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring Suheir Hammad, Muhammed Aram, and Walid Zaitar. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Suheir Hammad. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy.)
  - July 13, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:08); (Replay of audio documentary "Iraq How Can I forget?", NY-based performer writer H Raffo reads passages from "Nine Parts of Desire" and talks about Iraqi women and her work. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Iraqi-American performer Heather Raffo, voices from Iraq on audio documentary. Topics: Iraq, children, theater, women.)
  - July 20, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:52:52); (Guests report on NJ Shura Council for development of local projects for and by Muslims for youth and economy, legal services for local Muslims and detainees, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: Yasser Al-Menshawi, Attorney Alisha Mohammed of HELP service, Mazmu Mo Stevens of Sports Group. Topics: Muslim American, sports, civil rights, local services, immigration, detained Muslims.)
  - August 3, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:48:25); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring Susi Salameh and Kathy Najimi. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy.)
  - August 10, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:56:58); (Parsipur discusses her life and new book "Women Without Men", tracks from Iran musician Kalhor\'s "Mirror in The Sky" with Kurd vocalist Mouradi. Hosts/Producer: Barabara Nimri Aziz. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Iranian author Shanush Parsipur of "Women Without Men". Topics: Iran, Iranian writers, women, musicians, world music.)
  - August 17, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:57:04); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring political activists and artists; music mix by Nigel Parry; poet and writer Amina Taj; actress Najla Said; Josh Fox International WOW theater founder; actor Sarab Al-Shishekli of NAAP (Network of Arab American Professionals). Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy.)
  - August 24, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:55:12); (Guests Wahaj and Bashir on concepts of justice from Muslim and secular perspectives, criticism of HipHop image, and media stereotypes, listener calls. Hosts/Producer: Hassen Abdellah. Interviewees/Guests: NY-based Imam Suraj Wahaj, Mohammed Yaya Bashir. Topics: Muslim Americans, Islam, listener calls.)
  - September 7, 2004, 1 digital audio files (Duration: 0:59:39); (Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon, featuring film and Off-Broadway actor Ramzey Fargallah; opera singer Hanan Tara; actress Afaf Shawaa co-founder of Nibras Theater. Hosts/Producer: Dean Obeidallah, Maysoon Zayid. Interviewees/Guests: Fen Mejnoon with Dean and Maysoon. Topics: Arab American arts and comedy.)